SUPRESH MAHAJAN

6005536576 • msupresh31@gmail.com • https://supr3sh.github.io/

Summary

An IT Professional with 2+ years of experience in developing web applications and backend systems. Skilled at writing clear, concise code that is easy to maintain and troubleshoot. Successfully led a team of 3 deriving productivity and good results.

Experience

Stonewain Systems Inc

Chandigarh

Software Development Engineer

07/2022 - Present

- Implemented a new microservice to store static data of 70+ tables in caches.
- Successfully upgraded whole project from Java 8 to 11.
- Enhanced CI/CD pipeline with Python scripts, Maven, and Jenkins; cut deployment time by 35% and decreased manual intervention by 50%, leading to more reliable and faster releases.
- Incorporated **centralized config server** backed up by Gerrit to improve CI/CD pipeline.
- Trained a team of 3 members and led the team to automate the manual deployment and report generation processes.
- Created a Rule Engine in the Spring Boot application to apply more than 100 set of rules stated by the user

Stonewain Systems Inc.

Chandigarh

Software Development Intern

01/2022 - 06/2022

- Added bulk booking functionality via Rest API calls in the application using concepts of Spring AOP and Completable Future which improved performance by 56%.
- Worked on shifting a Web application from Monolithic to microservice architecture to improve performance by 40%.
- Added **Export to Excel** functionality to the application using Apache POI v5.2.3.

Skills

Technical Languages · Java 11 · JavaScript · HTML · Oracle SQL · C++ · Python

Frameworks · Spring Boot · Spring MVC · Hibernate · Rest APIs · Struts · Eh Cache

Tools · Postman · Maven · Docker · Jenkins · Git/Gerrit · Jira · CI/CD

Operating Systems · Linux · Windows

Education

Thapar Institute of Engineering and Technology Bachelors of Engineering

Patiala, Punjab

06/2018 - 06/2022

• Secured a CGPA of 8.21 in Computer Engineering branch.

Shiksha Niketan Sr. Sec. School

Jammu

Senior Education

2018

• Achieved 88.2% in 12th / Intermediate PCM (non-medical) affiliated to State Board.

Projects

Car rental application

- Developed of a robust car rental portal featuring user management, and approval workflows.
- Utilized HTML/JS/CSS for a user-friendly interface and Spring Boot/PostgreSQL for a scalable backend. This project demonstrates full-stack development and data management.

Savior Eye (Capstone Project)

Developed assistive technology for the blind using OpenCV, TensorFlow, and Raspberry Pi 5. This project integrates hardware and software to create an impactful solution for visually impaired individuals. This device leverages computer vision and machine learning to:

- Detect user location via GPS and geospatial data.
- Recognize familiar faces through facial recognition with TensorFlow.

Powered by CX7 Enhancy